

Shirsendu 'Troy' Karmakar

ENGINEER & HACKER

https://www.troysk.com

troy@troysk.com +91 7503455305

♠ Bagdogra Darjeeling, West Bengal, IN

in https://linkedin.com/in/shirsendukarmakar

• https://github.com/troysk

https://medium.com/@troysk

f https://facebook.com/shirsendu.karmakar

https://angel.co/troysk

https://stackoverflow.com/users/810911/troy-sk

https://twitter.com/troysk704

https://soundcloud.com/troysk

Troy hails from the foothills of Darjeeling, India. While earning his degrees he started freelancing as a web-developer. He crafted solutions using Wordpress, Joomla!, Drupal and PHP. After earning his masters degree he joined Tata Consultancy Services in Mumbai, India and used Java to help launch one of India's first SaaS products. He jumped onto the SlideShare wagon, which in 2011 was racing fast on Ruby-on-Rails. At SlideShare, he wore multiple hats and HTTParty'd till SlideShare's acquition by LinkedIn. At LinkedIn, he focused on integration between different systems and technical stack. He also worked on analytics product which processed 1 billion events a day! Troy guit LinkedIn to work on his startups QREOH and Solidry. Both of which were shut down at some point as oxygen dried up. Since then, he's been consulting with multiple companies helping them build high performance web apps and mobile apps. Somewhere between, he became a digital nomad and is currently on the lookout for a tribe to join.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Systemic JIA Foundation

Engineer

2015-12-01 - Present

http://systemicjia.org

Zeebra is a platform for rare diseases. By bringing rare disease patients together and sharing their data.

- Built the platform for collect data of patients
- Optimized UX • Sole Engineer

Tripoto

iCTO

2015-09-01 - 2015-11-30

https://www.tripoto.com

Tripoto is a website to share itneries.

- Built the unified search experience with third party integrations and recommendations Managed search optimizations
- Conceptualized newsfeed engagement and interactions

FreshMonk

Consultant

2015-06-01 - 2015-07-30

http://www.freshmonk.com

FreshMonk - Zero investment T-Shirt selling platform • Implemented the redesign of the product page

Modish Store

Consultant

2015-06-01 - 2015-11-01 http://www.modishstore.com

Modish Store sells exquisite handpicked furniture from across the world to its buyers in the USA.

- Built analytics report tracking system
- Executed multiple A/B Tests to optimize designs

SourceEasy

Consultant

2013-11-01 - 2014-03-31

http://www.sourceeasy.com

SourceEasy APIs for manufacting

Built version 1 of SourceEasy using Backbone and Ruby-on-Rails

Solidry

Founder

2013-06-20 - 2014-10-31

http://www.solidry.com Solidry was a 3D printing company.

• Conceptualized and built multiple 3D printers and 3D scanners • Built multiple e-commerce platforms using Ruby-on-Rails and Wordpress

QREOH

Founder

2013-04-24 - 2015-04-24 https://www.greoh.com

QREOH was a marketplace for independent designers.

- As a founder, worked on branding, customer relations and designer onboarding • Built a scalable marketplace platform using Ruby-on-Rails
- Worked on marketing and ran multiple successful content marketing campaigns Organized live events

LinkedIn

Senior Software Engineer 2012-05-03 - 2014-04-17

http://www.linkedin.com LinkedIn is the world's largest professional network

• Integrated SlideShare to use LinkedIn identity Built next generation analytics for authors of presentations

Upgraded Ruby and Rails from legacy versions

SlideShare Software Engineer

2011-04-04 - 2012-05-03

http://www.slideshare.net SlideShare is the world's largetst professional content sharing network

• Worked on multiple projects to make presentations more accessible to everyone • Ran multiple A/B tests to optimize conversion funnels of SlideShare's PRO offerings

- Performance optimizations on the frontend and backend
- **Tata Consutancy Services**

Assistant Systems Engineer

2009-11-30 - 2011-03-27 http://www.tcs.com

Tata Consutancy Services is one of the world's top software services company

• Worked on multiple multi-tanent apps for TCS's SaaS offering TCS iON Hacked Java Struts to work via AJAX on a legacy apps improving the UX

Freelancer

Developer

2004-03-15 - 2009-12-02 https://wwww.troysk.com

As a freelancer I worked on over 100 projects Built sites using Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal and PHP

Helped setting up local office networks and FM radio networks

Master of Computer application Master 2006-06-01 - 2009-06-01

University of North Bengal

Siliguri College Bachelor of Computer application

Bachelor

Web

2003-06-01 - 2006-05-30

SKILLS

EDUCATION

Ruby-on-Rails Sinatra

Intermediate

JavaScript Ruby

Microservices

Bootstrap

MySQL PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Redis Hadoop

PHP

Mobile

Intermediate

React Native

Ionic Platform

Full professional proficiency

Intermediate

Photoshop

Sketch

User Experience

LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

HBase

English

HTML CSS

Hindi

Bengali

Nepali French Reading comprehension Listening comprehension

Music Psytrance Western Classical Sufi

Full professional proficiency

ESP8266 Arduino Raspberry Pi Home Automation

Electronics

Full professional proficiency

Travelling Digital Nomad

South-East Asia